<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Poem blog</title><link>https://wasabina67.github.io/poem-blog/</link><description>Recent content on Poem blog</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.151.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 13:56:14 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wasabina67.github.io/poem-blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Smart Steps: Using Technology in Everyday Life</title><link>https://wasabina67.github.io/poem-blog/posts/2025-10-11-135614-using-technology/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 13:56:14 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://wasabina67.github.io/poem-blog/posts/2025-10-11-135614-using-technology/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Technology can make daily tasks easier and more fun.&lt;br&gt;
It acts like a helpful tool that fits in your pocket.&lt;br&gt;
You will find useful apps for learning, organizing, and communicating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, use a language app to learn new words by practicing for ten minutes a day.&lt;br&gt;
Set a timer on your phone to stay focused when you study.&lt;br&gt;
Use video calls to meet friends or work colleagues when you cannot meet in person.&lt;br&gt;
Try cloud storage such as Google Drive to save documents and share them quickly.&lt;br&gt;
Smart assistants can set reminders, play music, or answer quick questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fluent Habits: Practical Paths to English Mastery</title><link>https://wasabina67.github.io/poem-blog/posts/2025-10-11-135043-learning-english/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 13:50:43 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://wasabina67.github.io/poem-blog/posts/2025-10-11-135043-learning-english/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Learning English is less a race than a long conversation with the world.&lt;br&gt;
You will stumble, recalibrate, and eventually find rhythms that feel like your own.&lt;br&gt;
To accelerate progress, marry deliberate practice with curiosity and playful experimentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start with focused tasks such as shadowing dialogue from a podcast for ten minutes daily.&lt;br&gt;
For vocabulary, choose ten words per week and write three original sentences for each, using one in conversation.&lt;br&gt;
Practice grammar concretely by composing a short story using the past perfect and modal verbs to express counterfactuals.&lt;br&gt;
When listening, transcribe five minutes of audio and compare your version to the original to notice omitted words and linking sounds.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Happy Hobbies: Enjoy Your Free Time</title><link>https://wasabina67.github.io/poem-blog/posts/2025-10-11-131857-enjoying-hobbies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 13:18:57 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://wasabina67.github.io/poem-blog/posts/2025-10-11-131857-enjoying-hobbies/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Hobbies are fun.&lt;br&gt;
They help me relax.&lt;br&gt;
They give me energy.&lt;br&gt;
I enjoy many hobbies.&lt;br&gt;
I try them at home.&lt;br&gt;
Hobbies help me learn new skills.&lt;br&gt;
I feel proud when I finish a project.&lt;br&gt;
They give me time for myself.&lt;br&gt;
I like to share my hobbies with a friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading is a simple hobby.&lt;br&gt;
I read books in my room.&lt;br&gt;
I read for thirty minutes each day.&lt;br&gt;
Cooking is a good hobby too.&lt;br&gt;
I cook simple meals.&lt;br&gt;
I try a new recipe each week.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Simple Pet Care Tips for Happy Pets</title><link>https://wasabina67.github.io/poem-blog/posts/2025-10-11-131636-pet-care/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 13:16:36 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://wasabina67.github.io/poem-blog/posts/2025-10-11-131636-pet-care/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Pet care is fun and easy.&lt;br&gt;
You can help your pet stay safe.&lt;br&gt;
This blog gives simple tips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feed your pet at the same time each day.&lt;br&gt;
Use a clean bowl for water and food.&lt;br&gt;
For example, fill water in the morning and evening.&lt;br&gt;
Brush your cat with a soft brush each day.&lt;br&gt;
Walk your dog for at least thirty minutes.&lt;br&gt;
Play with your pet for fun and exercise.&lt;br&gt;
Check your pet’s fur and skin for any lumps.&lt;br&gt;
Give treats in small amounts after good behavior.&lt;br&gt;
Clean your pet’s bedding once a week.&lt;br&gt;
Take your pet to the vet for a checkup.&lt;br&gt;
Teach simple commands like sit and stay.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Weekend Wanderlust: Crafting Memorable Mini-Escapes</title><link>https://wasabina67.github.io/poem-blog/posts/2025-10-11-130816-weekend-travel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 13:08:16 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://wasabina67.github.io/poem-blog/posts/2025-10-11-130816-weekend-travel/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing rejuvenates the spirit like a spontaneous weekend escape to a nearby town.&lt;br&gt;
When time is scarce, crafting a lean itinerary that balances relaxation and exploration becomes an art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, you might start Saturday morning with an invigorating sunrise hike along a scenic trail before sampling local pastries at a hidden café around the corner.&lt;br&gt;
In the afternoon, wander through the artisan market to source handmade souvenirs and strike up conversations with friendly vendors.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Friends Like Sunshine: The Power of Small Acts</title><link>https://wasabina67.github.io/poem-blog/posts/2025-10-11-123208-friendship/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 12:32:08 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://wasabina67.github.io/poem-blog/posts/2025-10-11-123208-friendship/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever noticed how a simple text can brighten your day?&lt;br&gt;
That message from a friend is like a little ray of sunshine.&lt;br&gt;
Friendship is not just about big gestures; it grows from small moments we share every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, when my friend Nina saw me struggling with a heavy bag, she dropped everything and helped me carry it.&lt;br&gt;
I felt relief and trust in that moment.&lt;br&gt;
Another time, Jorge emailed me study tips before our exam.&lt;br&gt;
His advice made me calm and confident.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Escape the Routine: Your Perfect Weekend Getaway</title><link>https://wasabina67.github.io/poem-blog/posts/2025-10-11-120607-weekend-travel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://wasabina67.github.io/poem-blog/posts/2025-10-11-120607-weekend-travel/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Weekends are like a breath of fresh air after a busy week.&lt;br&gt;
You don&amp;rsquo;t need to book a long holiday to feel recharged.&lt;br&gt;
A weekend trip can be as simple as catching a local train or driving to a nearby town.&lt;br&gt;
For example, if you live in Tokyo, you might hop on the JR line to Kamakura.&lt;br&gt;
Spend the morning at a temple, enjoy matcha ice cream in the afternoon, and head home by dinner.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My First Poem</title><link>https://wasabina67.github.io/poem-blog/posts/my-first-poem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://wasabina67.github.io/poem-blog/posts/my-first-poem/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The sun rises in the morning sky,&lt;br&gt;
Birds are singing, flying high.&lt;br&gt;
I wake up with a happy smile,&lt;br&gt;
Ready to walk another mile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grass is green, the flowers bloom,&lt;br&gt;
Colors chase away the gloom.&lt;br&gt;
I take a breath of fresh, clean air,&lt;br&gt;
Life is beautiful everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friends will laugh and play with me,&lt;br&gt;
Together we are strong and free.&lt;br&gt;
Every day brings something new,&lt;br&gt;
Dreams can come if we stay true.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>